<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Malviya Devs</title>
    <link>https://malviya.dev/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Malviya Devs</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>© Aryansh Malviya {year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2022 00:49:22 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://malviya.dev/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Future of Advertising May Be Privacy</title>
      <link>https://malviya.dev/blog/future-of-advertising-may-be-privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2022 00:49:22 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malviya.dev/blog/future-of-advertising-may-be-privacy/</guid>
      <description>Some Background I have been deeply interested in technology, primarily, techspec. For those unfamiliar, &amp;rsquo;techspec&amp;rsquo; just means technological speculation.
This interest goes back for me over ten years ago when I started writing about technology and techspec on a blog that I had on Blogspot.
My mom wouldn&amp;rsquo;t give me any money to host my own site and I was still in middle school at the time. As such, I had thought that I should try to raise some money somehow through the internet to host my own website where I could run that blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Is Worth It, Always</title>
      <link>https://malviya.dev/blog/learning-is-worth-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2022 07:22:05 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malviya.dev/blog/learning-is-worth-it/</guid>
      <description>Live Demo: justremove
Github Repo: justremove_github
It may be a little late to try Typescript as the cool new thing in 2022, but I had never really thought that I needed to use it. I justified not using it like I always do, for anything new that I refuse to initially try, by saying that I didn&amp;rsquo;t really need it because I can already do it my way.
&amp;ldquo;My way&amp;rdquo; here being just vanilla JS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web as the Platform</title>
      <link>https://malviya.dev/blog/web-as-the-platform/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2022 18:28:35 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malviya.dev/blog/web-as-the-platform/</guid>
      <description>Every once in a while there are discussions about making things cross-platform or a big deal about it. Nowadays, this discussion is mostly limited to poweruser stuff like feature rich photo editing softwares, video editors or games.
A few years ago, there was a big concern about this but with the advent of Electron and the Web as a platform becoming even stronger, a new race has emerged that has the potential to put software innovation on a rocket ship.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Foundations Matter</title>
      <link>https://malviya.dev/blog/why-foundations-matter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2022 07:36:05 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malviya.dev/blog/why-foundations-matter/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR - without foundations you quickly forget them when working with high levels of abstraction and become headless chickens leading to unnecessary bottlenecks, complexities and brittle implementations.
There is a tendency in the software development landscape that exists today to simply pick up and use whatever gets the job done in the fastest way possible.
Fastest, purely in the terms of development time.
However, this philosophy has lead to a jungle of abstracted away complexities and ever rising memory demands, computational demands and, of course, bandwidth demands (network).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Writing</title>
      <link>https://malviya.dev/blog/on-writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2022 04:32:06 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malviya.dev/blog/on-writing/</guid>
      <description>Anyone can write. Anyone can tell a story.
But what is it to effective writing? (or effective storytelling?)
Every story, every piece needs a point, a moral, a takeaway.
What is it that after reading my story someone knows more of, definitively, than before they had read it?
That, is the question. It is a simple rule. As simple as &amp;ldquo;buy low, sell high&amp;rdquo;.
Everyone who sets out to write something knows that the other person takes something away from it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://malviya.dev/projects/temp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malviya.dev/projects/temp/</guid>
      <description>Projects Some projects that I have made previously, I&amp;rsquo;m constantly working on something or the other though, there&amp;rsquo;s a LIST~this is a todo to implement~ at the bottom of things that I intend to get to or am currently working on, many of these will be shelved, but it is worth trying.
APOD API Frontend Live Demo | Source Code
As an experiment to try out SolidJS I decided to implement a public API using it to get my hands somewhat dirty with it and understand its fundamentals.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
